Guide to the Alice Himelstein AREA Collection ca. 1983-1987 MSS.328
Fales Library and Special Collections
Alice Himelstein AREA Collection
circa 1983-1987
Fales Library and Special Collections
Nylon, Judy
Himelstein, Alice
MSS.328
0.2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The Alice Himelstein AREA Collection contains invitations and material related to New York's AREA nightclub, and includes material dating from 1983 to 1987.
Scope and Content
The Alice Himelstein AREA Collection contains material related to New York's AREA nightclub, extant from 1983 to 1987. Included in the collection are original invitations, press materials, flyers, and objects, mailed to and collected by Alice Himelstein.
Historical note
The AREA nightclub operated at 157 Hudson Street in New York from 1983 to 1987. The club, owned and operated by Eric and Christopher Goode, Shawn Hausman, and Darius Azari, was noted for its discriminating door policy and frequently changing designs (themes included "Sci Fi," "Night," "Suburbia," and "Gnarly"). The installations for the club's designs regularly included contributions from up-and-coming and established artists like Keith Haring, Jeff Koons, David Hockney, and Jean-Michel Basquiat. The club closed in 1987 with the farewell theme of "Childhood."
Arrangement
The Alice Himelstein AREA Collection consists of two boxes containing nine folders and eight unique objects.
Provenance
The Alice Himelstein AREA Collection was acquired from Judy Nylon by The Fales Library in 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Artists -- New York (State) -- New York.; Printed ephemera.; Mail Art.; Nightclubs.; Invitations.; Nylon, Judy
- Series I: Invitations
  - Art Area Flyer, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Egg Invitation, undated (Box 2, Object ID: 328.2.0001)
  - Halloween Invitation, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jewelry Box Invitation, undated (Box 2, Object ID: 328.2.0008)
  - New Year's Eve Invitation, undated (Box 2, Object ID: 328.2.0003)
  - New York Magazine Area Issue, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New York Telephone, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mousetrap Invitation, undated (Box 2, Object ID: 328.2.0005)
  - Obelisk Invitation, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Once Upon a Time, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Opening" Box, undated (Box 2, Object ID: 328.2.0007)
  - Pedal to the Metal Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Prizefight Invitation, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sandal Invitation, 1984 (Box 2, Object ID: 328.2.0006)
  - Soul Fridays, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Studio 54 Invitation, undated (Box 2, Object ID: 328.2.0004)
  - Sunglasses Invitation, undated (Box 2, Object ID: 328.2.0002)